Vinay Varshney

Senior Software Engineer







SUMMARY

Full Stack Engineer with 4+ years of experience in building scalable web applications. Excellent problem-solving skills, enthusiastic about learning new technologies and design efficient systems. Looking forward to work with a progressive team that utilizes my skills to the best of use.

SKILLS

- HTML5 & CSS
- JavaScript, Typescript
- Angular 6+
- MongoDB
- SQL

- Node.js
- Express.js
- AWS (S3 | EC2 | Route 53)
- GIT/ GitHub
- **Unit Testing**

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Iron Systems, Inc – Noida, India

Senior Software Engineer

June 2020 - Present

- Implement and ship new user-facing features to improve the user experience for 1M+ consumers.
- Maintaining and optimizing the mobile, web, and backend code structure as well as building new features on top of it.
- Took ownership of creating a monitoring map service for 10,000+ agents which provides live tracking and best route mapping.
- Created a centralized dashboard to provide monitoring and business metrics currently being used internally and by 100+ clients.
- Optimized highly available microservices cluster for providing notifications, activities performed, and distributed messaging by 40%.
- Lead an initiative to iteratively increase test coverage from ~5% to 80%.

Origa.ai - Noida, India

Aug 2019 - March 2020

Senior Engineer

- Led a team of 6 engineers and interns to deliver user-focused experience and solve complex problems.
- Reduced deployment time by 80% and eliminated deployment-related human errors.
- Optimized complete application both Web and Mobile resulting in a decrease of loading time by 25%.
- Performed code reviews and peer programming resulting in a 30% increase in overall productivity.
- Conducted unit and load testing for high-profile clients which reduced system failure rate by 70%.

Lumiq.ai – Noida, India

Oct 2018 - Aug 2019

Software Developer

- Started working on ORIGA.AI a B2B SaaS product consisting of mobile, web, and backend application from scratch.
- Created and optimized API endpoints that calculate the risks for loan disbursals, that serve 100,000+ users.
- Built automated monthly reports for both mobile and web apps which improved our performance reporting by 40%.
- Involved in solving critical product problems to ensure proper scalability and availability of the database.
- Grabbed 20 business clients and successful funding within the first 3 months of our product release.

HCL Technologies – Noida, India

Feb 2017 - Sep 2018

Senior Analyst

- Started as a Frontend Developer on a live project Carnival (a US-based project having a 5M+ user base).
- Implemented scalable angular structure and code which improved coding efficiency by 50%.
- Involved in stack migration to Angular and Node.js along with adding localization resulting in 2X faster page loads.
- Worked in an agile team to implement RESTful APIs that enabled our internal analytics team to increase reporting speed by 30%.
- Built a central dashboard allowing clients to dynamically visualize growth and user retention areas.

EDUCATION